[music]
>> All right. What's up, my friends?
Welcome to the complete set review
of Reality Fracture. I am amped for this
set. Uh
obviously, it's still in the early
phases, but for me this is the set of
the year. Looks so freaking cool. And
we're going to go over all the cards
that have been set for constructed and
limited. We did white and blue already.
If you missed those, go watch them on
YouTube.
If you're on YouTube, make sure you hit
like, comment, subscribe.
Support the content as always. A lot of
work goes into our set reviews, and your
support makes that possible. So,
hit the buttons. It's free. Costs
nothing. Do your thing, all right? So,
we're going to go over all the cards,
giving out the awards you know and love.
Don't forget, of course, the new brews
is happening on Wednesday, 23rd.
First chance to play with the new cards.
I'm very, very excited for that. Uh and
of course, we're brought to you by
Ultimate Guard, uh our wonderful
sponsor. I have some Exalted Angels to
sleeve up here. No uh no
uh mirror verse, whatever version of
Exalted Angel, huh?
>> [music]
>> Big miss there. Uh but Ultimate Guard's
the best in the business, of course. Uh
best sleeves, the Katanas. Deck boxes,
binders, and more. Highest quality.
Really cool designs as well. Uh their
Hobbit box is also so freaking [music]
cool. So, check them out uh
ultimateguard.com or wherever you find
Ultimate Guard products are sold near
you. Let's get into our [music] review
and start things off with Apex
Witchstalker. This is the black basic
land cycler.
It's a mana for a 6/4 menace.
When it enters or dies, you gain two
life and basic land cycling two.
Awesome.
Uh land cyclers
really, really good in the last few
sets, and this is, you know, close to
Honey Mammoth, you know, the the big six
drop comes into play, gains some life,
and stabilizes.
Four is certainly a lot less toughness
than six, so it's not as good of a
blocker. Uh makes up for that with
menace though. It's a much better
attacker.
Uh and uh
getting two life in, two life out.
It's not incredible. Uh but the land
cycler is obviously a big deal. There is
an uncommon zombify
uh which you can bring this back, which
is kind of cool. So, you can go you
know, turn your cycler this turn for
bring it back. We'll see that in a
little bit. Um but yeah, pretty good
land cycler. Definitely not not the best
of the bunch, but solid solid card for
sure. And uh plays well in limited.
Cast Away Doubt. Three mana for a
sorcery. Draw two and each player takes
two. Just your typical Read the Bones
variant. Um
I don't love these cards. Pretty good in
aggro as like a refill on like turn five
or six in limited. A little bit of
reach. Uh that being said, that's about
all it does. So, not a high pick by any
means. Kind of a sketchy card. It is
what it is.
Extended Absence.
Exciting common and common, being
totally honest. Uh but three mana for
four mana for an instant. Exile creature
or planeswalker and deal one and gain
one.
There's a lot of good little things
going on here with this card above the
usual like four mana instant kill a
creature. Uh exiling of course is very
good. Uh a lot better than killing it
for a lot of reasons. There are a lot of
planeswalkers in this set uh be it a
very large Jace token, more on that in a
bit, uh or one of the many rare or
mythic planeswalkers. This is a clean
way to deal with those, which could be a
pretty big deal actually. And it does a
bonus point of damage and also gains a
life. And there are life gain triggers
as well. Um the life gain archetype in
this format is uh black, sorry, uh green
white. So, this is of course not part of
that being a being a black card, but
you'll still see some life gain synergy
cards if you're playing black white or
green black. So, some value there, too.
And all that being said, it ends up
being the best black common.
Uh which you know, isn't the most
exciting thing of all time, but there it
is, common and common.
It's the usual. Pretty splashable, too.
Uh and yeah, if you're green-white, you
could splash this in theory, too, which
is kind of nice. So, good card. Very,
very solid card. Also, if you're soupy,
it could be a thing, too. So, card's
great.
Speaking of great removal spells, uh
Last Gasp. That's an old-school one. Uh
been been in standard in on and off for
the last 20 years or so.
Not as good as it used to be cuz things
are so much bigger these days, but I
think that uh
yeah, it's just a good removal spell,
you know. Not amazing, not a super high
pick, but very, very solid. And also,
cool cuz it's it's like it's a pump
spell, too, uh where they have a 5/5
attacking into a 3/3, you win the
combat. That's pretty sweet. So, good
solid card. I think it's already It's
It's classed out of standard right now
cuz there's the new -4/-4,
um
which is uh
obviously much better in constructed.
So, yeah. A limited card is what it is.
Then we have Rampart Hunter, 4/4, a 3/3,
deathtouch when it enters.
You have to get your bust 2/2 and
deathtouch on the turn. Uh just total
limited filler. Uh I would prefer not to
play this card in my draft deck if
possible.
Uh
yeah, it's basically basically it.
Rank Rat. It's Ravenous Rats, but it's a
zombie.
Sure. This card's basically in every
limited set these days. I will say with
so many
sets being released every year, it was
what, seven sets this year?
Limited has felt a little
paint-by-numbers at times. Um
where like, you know, there's just a
Ravenous Rat in literally every set with
a slight difference, which is like, all
right. You know, there's always a
Ravenous Rat, there's always a one-mana
sack-a-thing to kill a thing or pay
five, there's always a four-mana a
four-mana instant kill creature, and so
on and so forth. Um
that being said, the card's fine, you
know. It's obviously a fine limited
card. You've seen it a million times. Uh
being a zombie doesn't really matter,
but
however,
I don't like that art.
Uh why is that rat rubbing his ass up it
that character's lips? That's just
really, really creepy. I don't like it,
so we're going to go to the next page.
Screeching Soul Grazer. It's a matter
for a 1 4 flyer. Whenever it attacks,
deal one and gain one. So, there's a bit
of um
a bit of cross archetype synergy here uh
where
this is a black card.
The life gain, like I mentioned, is the
green white archetype. Uh the black red
archetype is like an aggro archetype
that cares about non-creature damage,
non-combat damage. Not Sorry, not not
non-creature, non-combat. This card
triggers that, and then it can trigger
your life gain stuff, too, in some weird
Absan or whatever else deck.
Pretty cool card. Uh definitely a
limited filler-esque where like this is
not a high pick by any means, uh but if
you are red black aggro, kind of like
this face burn stinger quill stuff, this
can do that for you. And if you end up
with some weird Absan deck, or you're
just like black white or green white has
some life gain triggers, this can do
that for you, too.
It's a pretty cool like glue limited
common. Not a high pick, but can, in the
right deck, do some good work.
Silence the Echo. Ah, you see,
it's not one mana and then four mana
kicker in this set. It's two mana with a
three mana kicker. Two mana,
uh destroy target creature or
planeswalker, uh but then you can
sacrifice a creature or planeswalker or
pay three. So, it's five mana to kill a
thing
uh or two mana sack and kill a thing.
This can sacrifice your Jace
planeswalker tokens, uh more on that in
a bit, which is kind of cute, actually.
You know, if you have a Jace on one,
it's a pretty free sacrifice, which is
kind of cool. So, there's a definite
value there. Probably why this card
costs one and uh sorry, two and three,
not one and four. I think this card
would have been pretty insane at one and
four uh in limited. So, still a good
card. Also, it can kill planeswalkers,
which is important, too.
Only a limited card, but a powerful one.
Solve for Disappointment. So, our first
Empowered Jace card in black. Two and a
blue for a sorcery. They reveal their
hand, take an online card, they discard
it. Empowered Jace one. So, what does
that mean? So, Empowered Jace is kind of
like a mass for uh this planeswalker
token of Jace, which simply has however
much loyalty the mass is, and then minus
one surveil one, minus two draw card.
If you Empowered Jace don't don't have a
Jace, make it with the many counters on
it. If you already have one, just add
the many counters to it. So, basically
you can shorthand um Empowered Jace
three is draw one. Empowered Jace one or
two is surveil one or two.
Uh and then obviously you can go from
there.
And uh this is effectively just a
Thoughtseize that surveils one.
Which is fine in limited. Uh this is
better than, you know, uh what's it
called? Uh Pilfer, whatever the
baseline, you know, version of this
effect is. Which is a fringe fringe
fringe player constructed.
Uh and then in limited it's pretty
solid. Will depend a lot on the speed of
the format. If it's a slow format, it's
going to be be pretty good card,
actually. In a faster format it won't be
as good. Um but yeah, kind of does what
it says on the box.
Pretty cool card.
I'm sorry, I can't read. Um
>> So, he's an idiot.
>> My bad. That makes it much worse. Uh
it's not a Thoughtseize, it's not land
permanent card, which makes this card
pretty awful. So, we're going to move on
to the next card here and go from there.
And uh the Jace token is not legendary,
but the mechanic specifically states
that like you can't make more than one.
If you already have one, you empower and
uh
and proliferate one you have. If you can
copy it in some way or pull it or not
proliferate um
uh what's it called? The copy
copy a token mechanic, you could do
that, sure, but it wouldn't do anything,
I guess, so.
Theoretical Necromancer, three mana for
a 4/1.
Has an ability in the graveyard, four
mana exile this from your graveyard and
uh increase raise dead.
Pretty good little common, honestly. 4/1
for three is pretty bad. But, you know,
you play this, trade it off, and then
late in the game get anything back.
There's a lot of self-mill in blue
black. The blue black archetype is all
about graveyard, you know, threshold
kind of stuff, so you can mill this
over. It's kind of cool.
That being said, it's pretty slow and
clunky, and not a very good body, so
feels like a filler card, uh but kind of
cool in those kind of decks. It's fine.
Void Extrapolator, two mana four eight
two two, enters prepared, has threshold
plus minus one, and has the omit
variables sorcery. So, kind of cool in
this set, uh
multiple cards use the same prepared
spell. So, omit variable is on multiple
different cards. It's just, you know,
one mana mill three.
Blue black's all about milling, filling
up the graveyard, getting threshold.
That's pretty cool. Um
yeah.
First pretty sweet, so
final two drop, nothing crazy, but good
archetype, you know, uh synergy bear.
Works fine in limited. Not great in
constructed, but
Next we have Break Under Pressure, three
mana four in instant. Target opponent
sacrifices a creature, planeswalker,
mana value uh greatest one they control,
and you gain two life. Um
kind of like a fine, you know, Hero's
Downfall variant. We've seen cards like
this see play in constructed when
there's large hexproof threats or things
that can't be targeted for whatever
reason. So, this is kind of like a
niche, you know, format dependent and or
sideboard card, uh that can see play in
certain scenarios, but often won't.
In limited still great, uh you know,
just whatever, clear your clear your
biggest thing, get to gain some life.
That's pretty sweet. But, in constructed
constructed this is a, uh you know, a
really, really fringe card to have in
the toolbox, and not too much more.
Here is the the
Danitha? I can't I just can't see the
name of this card, folks. I'm sorry. I'm
just
>> You're saying it wrong.
>> just too stupid.
>> It's Niv-Mizzet Osa.
>> is the black mirror version. Again,
there is a a uh
mirrored pair for all legends in a set
of a real version and a you know,
alternate universe version. This is the
mono black version, kind of like black
knight, white knight. Two two for three,
uh has first strike, cast spell at
target that an opponent or creature
opponent controls, put a counter on
this.
Just a kind of a fringe limited card.
Baseline stats are not great.
Um
Yeah, it's
Danitha
Danitha Danitha Danitha Danitha
>> [applause]
>> I am so great.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> [applause]
>> Ghalia Knight-Errant of Eos next. Uh
it's a better for a two one.
This is a two one menace and five mana
exile other creature card from your
graveyard to return this card
uh to the battle to the battlefield
tapped with a counter on it.
Card's pretty cool, actually.
Um
It's two one menace for two and dies,
you see bringing back over and over
again. Um
uh
Yeah, solid card.
Solid two drop, good limited card, plays
well in the uh blue black uh you know,
mill yourself threshold deck. Uh
constructed is probably not good enough.
It's a zombie, which might matter, but
it's a cool limited card for the most
part and not too much else.
Oh my god.
Oh.
>> I bet you weren't expecting that one,
god.
>> If uh this is the receivables, this
would win the char rumbler award for
weirdest card in the set.
Loot the anomaly
horrifying. Um
for so many reasons.
Better for a negative two
four.
If Loot's power is negative he assigns
combat damage as though his power were
positive.
So,
the idea here is that if you were to
give this, you know, -5 -0, like the
blue counter spell does, that's like a
pump spell. So, we have a That's a way
to pump things. It's really weird.
Then has threshold, so I could creature
or planeswalker, it gets -2 -0 to end of
turn.
Only if you have threshold, and again,
it's basically just like +2 +0.
Um
really, really weird.
Last Gasp, -3 -3, is not a giant growth
because the toughness still affects it.
So,
if you were to cast lightning uh I'm
sorry, a
a Last Gasp on this,
you would effectively have a 5/1.
Uh which is
just really damn weird.
This is going to be a fun card in
limited. It's not playable otherwise,
unless it's some weird combo or
whatever.
Uh yeah. Card gives me a headache. I
don't even want to look at it anymore.
Mabel, Bitter Recluse. Mabel has turned
to the dark side here.
One mana for a 1/1 death touch. Always a
good stat line in limited. When it
enters, remove up to three counters from
a target creature or planeswalker.
This card is great in limited. Uh this
card comes in, eats a Jace token, uh
removes plus and minus one counters from
all over the place.
Uh and then of course, uh again, the
baseline stats of 1/1 death touch is
fantastic.
Constructed, I think this card could be
a sideboard card in constructed,
uh against planeswalker decks or some
sort of counter things, you know.
If there was some good creature that was
like a 0/0 with counters on it kind of
thing or whatever else, yeah, Moonshadow
could be a thing. So, I think this card
has a home in constructed, possibly in
sideboards. It's just so cheap. Uh and
then in limited, of course, this card is
super solid. So, card's great. Mabel
looking good in black.
Massacre Girl, Most Wanted. Five mana
for a 4/4.
Whenever another creature or
planeswalker you control dies, one
damage to an opponent and you gain one
life. Uh so again, this card plays on
both sides of the ball as far as the
black red direct damage aggro archetype
and the green white life gain cards,
which is kind of cool.
Uh and then, whenever an opponent is
dealt non-combat damage, put a counter
on Masked Girl. So again, that's part of
the kind of the red red black theme. So
it's a red black card for sure, but it
can be doing life and stuff also. Fine
limited card. I think I think this
card's pretty good. Um
not too hard to make it decently sized,
does have some synergy stuff. Good draft
card. I like it.
Multiply by zero.
Wait. What?
>> No!
>> You can't do that.
Um
So, I guess you can. I'm sorry. You You
can't Whatever, man.
>> Just in a bad
>> Just divide by zero. You can't do more
than zero is always whatever. It's fine.
So, you get the idea. So, two and a red
instant, target creature's base power
and toughness 0/0 until end of turn.
So, at first glance, this looks like
Doom Blade, right? Oh my god, this just
kills anything for the most part.
Doesn't really work like that
uh because say the creature has a plus
one plus one counter on it for whatever
reason. Now, it just doesn't kill it at
all. It just um It does shrink it
potentially, but it's not a kill spell.
So, it's kind of like Heartless Act in
that regard where like it can't kill
things with counters on it.
Also, what about equipment or global
pump effects or whatever else, you know?
So,
I
don't know [clears throat] exactly what,
you know, it's
it's going to depend on the the texture
of all the cards in the format as far as
far as what this kills. It does kill
things that are indestructible, which is
kind of cool.
Um
but there isn't really a best in slot uh
Doom Blade in standard right now anyway.
This might end up being that, but it is
a little more fringe than it looks, I
think. That being said, it's still quite
good.
Uh it's pretty cool, and the art is out
of this world good. I love it.
Um but yeah, cool card. Just be
cognizant of the downsides, cuz they are
numerous uh and and risky. So, uh
yeah, really really cool art. Love this
card. Great limited card, too. Just
solid.
Profane Sinister Mastermind.
Two mana for a 5/5, Ella. Threshold, you
can't cast this spell unless there are
seven or more cards in your graveyard.
So, you literally just can't cast it.
Has menace and has one black. Discard
this card to give a creature minus three
minus one until end of turn.
It's close, you know, um the ability to
use extra copies is a rule that's kind
of nice. That being said, only one
toughness is rough. Uh the blue black
archetype is all about threshold, so
shouldn't be too hard to get there and
cast this eventually, but it's a little
a little slow in that regard.
Um
Constructed-wise, you just
I don't even know if a vanilla 5/5 for
three would be playable in Constructed
these days. Uh so, more of a limited
card, but pretty good in limited, I
think. It's solid.
Um
It's pretty cool.
Rewrite Regrets. Three mana for a four
mana for a sorcery. Zombify a creature
mana value six or less. And then power
Jace, too.
For Constructed, um
you got to bring back the big big boom
booms, the the seven, eight, and nines,
I think. So, not really a starter there.
I think Zombify's already in standard,
too. Um in Foundations, I think. I'm not
sure, though. Uh but Empower Jace, too,
is pretty cool. And of course, in
limited, this card plays really well in
this blue black archetype, where you're
just milling things constantly. The six
mana land cycler in black uh is the
perfect thing to return with this also
as well. So, I think this is a pretty
cool limited card uh for your graveyard
threshold deck.
I probably wouldn't play this without a
lot of good self-mill, but if you have
that and a land cycler, I think it's
pretty cool. And the empowered Jace has
some upside. Jace can surveil, too. Puts
things in the graveyard, too. So, it's
fine. Nothing to write home about.
Or rewrite home about. Uh
but yeah, it can return planeswalkers,
too, which is kind of cool.
So, that might be a a possible
constructed application, but just like
play a better card and cast the card.
Just I don't know.
Terminal Criticism, brutal. Three mana
for an instant, destroy target creature
or planeswalker if it's blue or red and
gain one life. This is the uh again
color-shifted version of the uh
the kill a green or white creature and
gain one life uh from whatever set that
was in. And uh this is a sideboard card
that will be applicable in some
scenarios and not in others. You get the
idea.
Teo, Diamond Blade Mage.
Three mana for a a 3/1 flash.
Whenever it enters a permanent you
control gains death touch until end of
turn. Put a counter on it if it is a
creature and put a loyalty counter on it
if it's a planeswalker.
So, kind of weird because typically you
use death touch to trade in combat. So,
like putting the extra counter on your
creature
almost doesn't matter. Um
kind of awkward.
You can target itself, I guess, uh but I
guess putting a death touch count death
touch on a planeswalker is kind of
amusing. Or if it has like a damage
effect, it's kind of cute, but this card
seems far more cute than good. Uh the
body is not great, the ability is not
great.
It's a fringe limited card, not much
more.
Tinybones is back!
Three mana for a 2/1 ETB opponent
discards a card.
Whenever opponent discards one or more
cards, they take one damage.
Card's good. You know, 2/1 for three,
discard a card is like fine in limited.
And then of course this helps to trigger
your red black face burn effects. Yeah.
Tiny bones is great.
I got nothing bad to say about tiny
bones, that's for sure.
Way of the deathbringer. So again, there
are two pieces of enchantments in every
color that make a adjacent do a thing.
Mana four a enchantment empower Jace
five. Which is a big deal.
Also gives planeswalkers you control
minus two. Sacrifice a creature and make
a 4-4 with trample.
Card's pretty good, you know.
This is potentially
play a Jace draw card, the next turn
sacrifice and make a 4-4. That's pretty
awesome.
And then of course empower Jace is a lot
of flexibility in all directions, which
is really really fun.
Definitely want to be playing some
stinkers to sacrifice. Don't want to
sacrifice a you know, a um
you know, a 2-2 or 3-3 or whatever.
But yeah.
Card's nice.
Uh
more of a limited card. I don't think
this card's good enough for constructed,
but a cool limited card at that.
And then there's Way of the Necromancer.
Two and a four a enchantment that enters
and powers Jace only two.
Whenever a creature you control dies,
you put a loyalty counter on each
planeswalker you control.
So for limited this is this is pretty
sweet. As long as you have Jace in play,
things just die, counters go up. Notice
not one or more. So this can
you know, four things die in a combat
give you four counters. And it's also
each planeswalker you control, which can
add up to a lot.
In theory, if you were playing some sort
of like, you know, planeswalker super
friends deck where they all make tokens,
this could be a pretty sick way to kind
of go up a ladder.
But I don't know if it's good enough at
face value, honestly. Uh because you're
you need to be having creatures and
planeswalkers. It's a lot of moving
parts, you know.
Uh but it's a it's a cool card. It's
cheap as well, which I kind of like.
Um
It's cool. Cool card.
Can limited I mean I'm not sure on
limited. Uh it's might not be might not
be there all the way.
Winter tormented loser.
Sorry. Sorry, Lona. My bad. Two mana for
a 1/3. When Winter enters, sacrifice a
creature or planeswalker, and when you
do, each opponent sacrifices a creature
of their choice.
And Winter gets plus one plus zero for
each creature and planeswalker card in
your graveyard.
Pretty solid card, honestly, where
this sort of like flashback marauder
effect is usually pretty good if you
build your deck around it. Uh and then
this will be sized up. Assuming this
will be a 3/3 or a 4/4 or a 4/3 or
something like that. You know, it's
going to be a lot bigger than a a
flashback marauder would usually be. And
also, sacrificing a Jace token on one is
fantastic.
Uh it's really really good. An absolute
floor is you can sac it can sac itself.
So, if they have a creature in play,
they want a creature in play, you can
just play it and sacrifice it. Um
Yeah. So, this card's great. I think
this card's quite good. It's probably
not good enough for constructed. Uh
there were points in time where
flashback marauder and playcrafter were
playable uh standard cards, I know cuz I
love those cards.
I don't think uh that that time is now,
but yeah. And uh this dude also loves
the cure.
Yargle, Glutton of Urborg. This is
actual Yargle. Let's skip leg day. And
it's not very good, but it's cool. So,
we're just going to smile and nod at
Yargle and be like, "I'm glad you're
here, bud."
Dark matter manipulator. One mana for a
1/2. Now we're in the rares. When it
enters, mill three cards, and it gets
plus two plus zero for every seven cards
in your graveyard. So, let's just say
threshold plus two plus zero. So, this
card's kind of gas. Um
we don't really
almost ever see the creature ETB mill X
enablers at one mana, they're almost
always two.
And uh
you know, two is
not you know, say to away finder kind of
cards is often a little too high on the
curve. So, this is in such a this is
Stitcher Supplier uh on on mega upside.
You don't get the uh the the the death
trigger, but you do get the ability to
actually have a threat, which is great.
And it's you know, you're already you
know, almost halfway to having a one one
mana 3 2, which is fantastic. If you're
playing fetch lands or spells or other
self mill or whatever it is,
not too hard to make this thing into a 3
2, and you know, you're milling your
Bloodghasts and whatever else too.
I think the card is kind of great. Uh I
like the card a lot. Um I'm doing a cube
update for our boys weekend coming up,
and uh this is a card that I'm pretty
excited to add to the cube as well, cuz
this card just seems awesome. So,
yeah, big fan. Much better than a card
like Stitcher Supplier uh in limited. In
constructed, I think it might be better
also. And Supplier is a card that's seen
play a lot of times over the years. So,
card's great, big fan.
Uh and limited card seems great, too,
because you just want to do the uh
graveyard thing in in blue black. So,
big fan of this card, like it a lot.
Extrapolate the impossible. Ooh, boy.
>> Inconceivable.
>> Weird one. Tomato sorcery. You may
reveal exactly two cards you own with
different names from outside the game.
Opponent chooses one of those cards, and
you put it in your hand.
Weird card. So, we have a wish that's
not always going to be a wish.
Um
Pretty strange one.
You might be able to set up scenarios
where like, you know, you can get two of
the same type of card you want. Say you
get an Anger of the Gods and a
Brotherhoods End or something like that.
But I don't know if adding two uh
two to the cost of that card is like,
you know, is five mana Anger of the Gods
good? No, not really.
Could there be some sort of like combo
with this? I don't know. It's a really
weird card. I don't think it's very
good.
Um
I think that maybe
you have some sort of potential like
combo applications.
What if you had like, you know, a
Soul-Guide Lantern and a Tormod's Crypt
for some main deck graveyard hate? I
don't know.
Really, really weird card.
Mostly unplayable in limited. And
constructed
might need to have I I don't know,
honestly. This is one where let's let
time decide cuz I'm too stupid to figure
it out.
>> Okay.
That one's on me.
>> Next up we have Gideon the Oathless,
three mana for a 3/3. Uh has ward,
discard a card. Great, great text line.
Whenever a creature an opponent controls
enters, they uh they take one. And if an
opponent activates a loyalty ability,
they take one.
Fine card, you know.
Um not amazing uh by any means. It's a
great limited card because it just, you
know, good abilities, good stat line,
etc.
Constructed if there was some sort of
token deck, I suppose this is is a fine
hate piece for that.
I guess if there's some planeswalker
control deck, this card lines up okay, I
guess. Hard to kill.
Makes planeswalkers annoying, but
that being said, this is mostly just
like a, you know, good limited card.
I guess there's like that token
mobilized Boros deck, be pretty good
against that.
Uh
but yeah, just a fine on rate card. It's
not that exciting.
Lich's
Relic.
>> [snoring]
>> Maybe this is a weird one, folks. Um
maybe I'm just too crude bent blade um
pulled from a from The Hobbit.
>> Do not want any adventures here, thank
you. Not today.
>> But this card looks kind of nice to me.
One black for an equipment, effectively
three mana, because when you play it,
you can pay two, and if you do, just
destroy a creature or planeswalker,
right?
Then it has equipped creature gets plus
two, plus one, and equip for two.
So, you can just play this on turn
three. It's kind of like chainsaw in
that regard, right? And you all know how
much I love chainsaw. Just play it on
turn three, kill a thing, and now you
have this equipment in play, which is
kind of sitting there. You can use it as
an equipment, just like straight up,
uh or you can maybe bounce it, sacrifice
it, whatever else it might be.
It's pretty cool, uh honestly. So, kind
of a cool card.
I don't know
exactly where it goes, or what it does,
or whatever else. Um and there, you
know, the equipment energy is definitely
not in black. Hi Karn, how are you?
Um
but yeah, I I I don't know exactly what
it is. I just think this card looks
sweet. Uh it is tutor-able from Tezzeret
and Brightclimb Gearhulk, which is kind
of cool.
Uh it triggers chain foster. There are a
lot of uh equipment-based things
happening in standard right now, and I
just get this card, I get get get good
vibes. So, that's why it's a sleeper
card. In limited, this card is unreal.
Um
Cruel Bent Blade was, you know, one of
the best cards in that format, and this
is just a strictly better Cruel Bent
Blade in literally every sense of the
word. So, card's great. Plus, it will
nurture you basically, which is kind of
cool. So, that's my sleeper card for
black, Lich's Relic.
Liliana, the Repentant, creature version
of Liliana. Two mana for a 2/2. Whenever
another creature or planeswalker enters
mill two. And then you can exhaust it
for six mana to return a creature or
planeswalker from the battlefield and
put a counter on Liliana.
I mean,
this card is like good. It's not great.
It's a great limited card, cuz it's just
like
pretty low opportunity cost for a
two-drop.
Constructed-wise, I don't think this
card is that good, uh because six mana
to reanimate is kind of bad.
You can mill some cards like decently
well with this, but
kind of feels like an uncommon to me,
honestly. So, uh
yeah, it's fine. Sure.
Rise of the Deathbringer. I'm going to
for an instant, choose one. Draw cards
equal to grace power of creatures you
control and lose that much life. Uh or
all creatures get minus two minus three.
Neither side of the ball here is
particularly appealing. It's a bad card
draw spell on a bad super.
In limited, I'm sure you could find some
cool use for this, but
don't think this card is a
is very good.
>> Still a piece of garbage. [music]
>> Sanctum Weaver, a mana for a 3/2. When
this enters, empower Jace one.
Planeswalkers you control aren't put
into their graveyards for having zero
loyalty.
And planeswalkers you control have plus
two loyalty. This planeswalker deals one
damage each opponent and you gain one
life.
Very unique card. Um
a planeswalker in play on zero cuz it'll
still be plused, obviously. So,
you could have a planeswalker like die,
still live, and then next turn just plus
it, which is kind of cool.
That being said,
what
are you doing with
you know, this creature in your
planeswalker deck where like you're not
playing many creatures and they're going
to kill with their removal spells and
stuff like it just
a really, really weird card. Uh it is
cute that you could just plus the Jace
immediately and you could plus it and
then minus it, plus it and then minus it
on that pattern.
But like it's just a vanilla 3/2. So,
I don't know. And I believe you can
minus
I don't know, actually. Judge, can you
minus with loyalty that you don't have?
So, you can't minus what you don't got.
Uh so, uh cuz it's a cost. So,
that's a that's a that's a big deal. Uh
but yeah, it's a weird card. It's a cool
It's a great card for limited. Uh, but
constructed wise, I'm not so sure what
you do with this card. It's just a very
strange one.
Vraska's Final Mercy.
>> It's a trap.
>> Cool story beat. Uh, but not a very good
card, I don't think. Five black sorcery,
choose one. Lose two life and kill a
creature or planeswalker, which is
pretty bad, honestly. You know, it's a a
much, much worse bitter triumph. Or lose
two life and power Jace six, which is a
much, much worse uh, sign in blood.
So,
that
makes this card look pretty bad to me.
And power Jace six is a lot if you're
like trying to like get up to 25 Jaces
for the planeswalker or whatever else it
might be, but
I think this card's pretty sketch. I
really think modern day magic is so fast
and any life loss card is a huge, huge
downside. Uh,
so yeah, I think this card's pretty meh.
That's trap card for uh, for black
Vraska's Final Mercy. Neither mode here
is particularly great and they're not
not that flexible, so.
Then we get to our mythics. You get
Bloodline Keeper, Bloodline Reconnector,
then a 4/2/2. Beginning of each end
step, if two or more creatures died this
turn, becomes prepared, which is a lot.
It's a hard thing to meet. Uh, and the
spell is Ancestral Cravings. One black
instant, target player draws three and
loses three. So, kind of cute. You can
bolt them or draw yourself. Uh, that
being said, this is a commander card.
This is like a, you know, oh, things are
dying on your turn? Oh, on your turn
also? I'm going to keep casting this
card over and over again while I have 40
life. Um,
in standard, I think this card is just
totally unplayable.
Uh, and then in limited, it's fine. You
know, the floor is a 2/2, whatever.
Uh, but yeah, this card's
a lot of uh, pomp and circumstance, but
it's not very good.
However, one really cool card is Dark
Light Phoenix.
Our best in show award winner.
This card's awesome.
Four mana for a 4/3 flyer with haste.
So, it's an Arclight Phoenix. But,
rather than have a spell-based way to
return, it returns being combat your
turn if two or more creatures die this
turn. Note that it does not necessarily
mean under your control or your
opponent's control. So,
in some sort of sacrifice deck,
this card is pretty awesome. There are
multiple effects that make you
both players sacrifice a creature, or I
sacrifice my thing to kill your thing,
whatever else it might be.
Um sure, evoking a creature to kill a
thing. Empty this works well there, too.
Uh and then various sacrifice effects
just in general. And this plays really
well with sacrifice, graveyard, surveil
kind of stuff.
Um
you got to get it in the bin, which is
the hard part. But, pretty awesome,
pretty resilient.
Yeah.
I mean, this card's just super sweet. I
don't know what to tell you. This card's
awesome.
Uh so, yeah. Really, really cool stuff.
Uh great in limited, too, cuz a 4/3
flying haste for three is good enough as
it is anyway. And um yeah, card's dope.
Best in show for black. I have Darklight
Phoenix. I am very excited to brew with
this card.
Garruk, veiled butcher. There are There
are more planeswalkers in this set than
I'm pretty sure there are in standard
right now.
Total. Which is kind of wild. Garruk,
veiled butcher is five mana for a five
loyalty planeswalker. If a creature or
planeswalker controls would die, exile
it instead. So, mildly good passive.
Plus two, gives a creature minus four
minus one. So, it can defend It can
defend itself and kill small creatures.
Minus two, each player sacrifices a
creature. And if you sacrifice a
creature this way,
uh
you get a 4/4, which is pretty sweet.
Kind of in sort of like sacrifice-y,
whatever, uh deck. It's cool. And then
each opponent discards two cards uh for
minus three. For each opponent who
didn't discard two nonland cards this
way, you draw a card. So, it's kind of a
It can kind of just mind rot your
opponent, too. So, the fact that this is
good against creatures and also can make
creatures and also is good against
non-creatures. It's kind of cool. That
being said, the the bar for a five mana
planeswalker is pretty high. A lot of
competition in standard is really fast.
I don't think this card will make it
constructed, honestly.
I just don't think there's enough
enough, you know, if this was a a
six-set standard format, sure, but this
is a 26-set standard format and there's
ain't no room for a card like this. So,
it's a fantastic limited card, really
really good. But constructed, I just
don't think it's good enough.
Overwrite the Multiverse, six mana for a
mythic sorcery.
Exile all creatures and power Jace X
where X is the number of creatures
exiled in this way.
This card's pretty good.
This is sort of video Sunfall-esque. It
costs one more mana,
but if you exile at least three or more
creatures, you'll draw a card. And say
it's six or seven creatures, some some
larger amount. Now you have this huge
empowered Jace in play, where you can
draw multiple cards and surveil.
That's pretty good.
Very glad this card cost six and not
five because Sunfall was egregious.
But yeah, this card's nice. It's clunky.
It's a little slow, very very powerful.
And then probably just completely
unbeatable in limited like Sunfall was,
where your opponent casts this, you just
slam your head on the table and
get really really mad because you are in
big big doo-doo.
So, to recap in black, best in show is
Darklight Phoenix. Legion's Landing is
our sleeper card. Vraska's Final Memory
Final Mercy is our trap card. And
Extended Absence is our bomb in common.
Got a little little uh
little frozen here. Fix that in a
second. So, like I was guys, support the
content. Write what's coming up and
peace.